POLINA STEINMÜLLER

SFNIOR ACCOUNTANT

polina.steinmueller@yahoo.com



+49 176 21 74 49 07



Steglitzer Damm 86 12169 Berlin



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly motivated, details-committed and love for new knowledge accountant with over 9 years of experience in accountancy. I have already gained experience not only working in different areas in accounting department, but also in different companies that work in different fields. I am open to new challenges.

SKILLS

Organisation and attention to detail

Adaptability

Deductive reasoning

Time Management

Creativity

Ability to learn

Agile

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE Finance Management IUBH Internationale Hochschule (Distance learning) June 2019 – June 2024

BACHELOR'S DEGREE Business Studies RISEBA University of Applied Sciences (Distance learning) February 2017 – May 2019

> ACCA Student June 2018 - Present

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR ACCOUNTANT

Care.com Europe GmbH, Berlin, DE / March 2023 - Present

- Account Payables
- Account Receivables
- Bank inc. Preparation and setting of payment runs
- Month End Closing Preparation and Reporting
- Reporting to US HQ
- Contact person for other departments in general finance questions
- Office Assets
- Accrual bookings

ACCOUNTAN in areas: all-round

MatchX GmbH, Berlin, DE / November 2022 - March 2023

- Setting up accounting department and optimasing the processes
- Assistance with year-end closing
- Cooperation with tax consultants, finance and statistics offices
- Support and preparation of monthly VAT returns in DE and EU
- Account payables and account receivables
- Support with bank and payments
- Reporting and reconciliations of business transactions
- Contact person for other departments in general finance questions

ACCOUNTAN in areas: accounts payable, accounts receivable, travel expenses ib vogt GmbH, Berlin, DE / January 2020 – October 2022

- Creating outgoing invoices and optimasing the process
- Participating in organisation of workflow and supporting recording process of travel expenses in accounting books
- Participating in integration of the new version of the accounting program system
- Processing incoming invoices
- Verifying accounts payable and accounts receivable accounts

POLINA STEINMÜLLER

SFNIOR ACCOUNTANT

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office 365:

Word, Excel, Outlook (confident user)

Microsoft Dynamics NAV (confident user)

SAP (beginner)

Datev Online (beginner)

WorkDay (confident user)

Languages

German (Completed B2 certificate)

English (Fluent due to living in UK)

Russian (Mother language)

EXPERIENCE continued

ACCOUNTANT REAL ESTATE MANAGEMENT, general accountant MVGM / JLL, Berlin, DE / October – December 2019

- Account Payables
- Account Receivables
- Reporting for monthly and quarterly financial statements
- Authorization of bank payments
- Verification of general ledger accounts

ACCOUNTANT

Robert Half Deutschland GmbH & Co. KG Berlin, DE / September 2017 - October 2019)

Clients worked with through temp agency:

- ◆ Deutsche Bahn AG (hahn+friends finance GmbH & Co. KG), Berlin, DE / September 2017 – January 2018
- ❖ Apassionata World GmbH, Berlin, DE / January October 2018
- ❖ The KaDeWe Group, Berlin, DE / November 2018 October 2019
- Participated in Project "Support for financial statements"
- Supported internal accountants in annual financial closing
- Account Payables
- Account Receivables
- Travel Expenses

ACCOUNTANT in areas: accounts payable, accounts receivable, travel expenses. Including office and CEO support.

Translog Ltd, Sankt-Petersburg, RU / July 2014 - December 2015

- Introduced and optimised full documental workflow in the company
- Processed all incoming/outgoing invoices
- Reported on costs and profits to the management
- Participated in preparation of monthly financial statements
- Administrated and managed all office questions and inquiries
- Organised business trips
- Developed and ordered promotional products

SPECIALIST of the administrative department CJSC Eurosib-Logistics, Sankt-Petersburg, RU / July 2012 – July 2014

- Administrated and managed all office questions and inquiries
- Created monthly/quarterly reports and budgets regarding office expenses
- Organised business trips
- Supported document circulation in the company